PRESTON BURTON

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

□ preston.burton@gmail.com □ prestonburton.dev □ 9137355148 □ Eugene, Oregon GMT-7
□ preston-burton-447108186/ □ Oliver-Strange

SUMMARY

Experienced Assistant Manager breaking into the Web Dev world. Student of Lambda School skilled in: Full-Stack Development, Responsive Design, Accessibility, Styling, and Database Management. I am ready to learn and grow with a team that has a passion for their products. Making the world a better place with people who work well together is the dream I want to make into reality.

EDUCATION

Lambda School

Mar. 2019 to Nov. 2019

Full Stack Web Development 2019

Fifteen week Full Stack cirriculm, Eight week capstone project, Nine weeks of Computer Science 9hrs/ day M-F

Emphasis on peer programming, team collaboration, and real world practices

EMPLOYMENT

Vero Espresso House Assistant Manager

Eugene, Oregon Sept. 2015 to Current

I help train new employees, design schedules, place orders, and ensure the quality of our product.

Lambda School Team Lead

Remote July 2019 to Aug. 2019

I was hired to be the Team Lead for my capstone project at Lambda School. Over the course of seven weeks, I helped my four person team of full stack web developers: write feature canvases and plan the product cycles, design the back end database, and help role out features on our front end client. I used Trello, Notion, Slack, Zoom, and Github to keep our team in sync and moving at fast pace.

PROJECTS

Go Have Fun - Capstone Project

July 2019 to Aug. 2019

I was the Team Lead and a developer for my capstone project. Beyond my Team Lead duties, I designed the PostgreSQL database and helped create several of the front end React components. Our application uses Google Maps API to Geo-locate users, if allowed, and shows them any events, posted to the site by other users, around their location. Auth0 handled a secure login required to post events. I helped wrap up the project by creating a future goals document for the next team that takes our project as a build-on.

Art-folio

Apr. 2019 to Apr. 2019

I designed the landing site for a React application. It was my first build week at Lambda and my first exposure to working on a team coding project. I learned the importance of communicating design and feature implementation with the team, while also staying on top of my own part of the project.

SKILLS

TEAMWORK: Slack, Zoom, Trello, Github, Notion, Kanban Boards, Agile/Scrum **FULL STACK:** React / Node, PostgreSQL, Sass / Less , Python3, Responsive Styling, NPM / YARN, Auth0, Google APIs, Jest / Cypress Testing